- question: "When running an Ad-Hoc Ansible command, you are running Ansible without a _______ :"
  answers:
    - "ansible.cfg"
    - "inventory file"
    - "playbook"
    - "module"
  correct: "playbook"
  day: 2

- question: "What file lists connection info (IP address, user name) for hosts and groups of hosts?"
  answers:
    - "playbook"
    - "module"
    - "inventory"
    - "ansible.cfg"
  correct: "inventory"
  day: 2

- question: "If you wanted to set a default location for where Ansible looks for your inventory file, where would you add that rule?"
  answers:
    - "playbook"
    - "module"
    - "inventory"
    - "ansible.cfg"
  correct: "ansible.cfg"
  day: 2

- question: "List the following from LARGEST to SMALLEST:"
  answers:
    - "Plays, Playbooks, Tasks"
    - "Tasks, Playbooks, Plays"
    - "Playbooks, Plays, Tasks"
  correct: "Playbooks, Plays, Tasks"
  day: 2

- question: "In Ansible, what is idempotence?"
  answers:
    - "Makes a change the first time ONLY"
    - "Makes a change every time."
    - "Throws an error if a change must be made more than once."
  correct: "Makes a change the first time ONLY"
  day: 3

- question: "Uh oh! Your host doesn't have Python installed! What module will you likely use to automate installing Python on hosts?"
  answers:
    - "apt"
    - "yum"
    - "raw"
    - "lineinfile"
  correct: "raw"
  day: 3

- question: "When you use a LOOP, what is the variable that represents each item being returned from the loop?"
  answers:
    - "x"
    - "item"
    - "element"
    - "state"
  correct: "item"
  day: 3

- question: "What keyword allows us to set a condition that must be met before a task runs?"
  answers:
    - "if"
    - "try"
    - "when"
    - "check"
  correct: "when"
  day: 3

- question: "Which of the modules that we learned about yesterday seems like it'd be most useful to you? Can you provide a use case of where you think you could use it?"
  answers:
    - "debug"
    - "copy"
    - "template"
    - "yum"
  correct: "debug"
  day: 3

- question: "With those four variables defined at the top, which of the four lines in the Jinja2 template WILL NOT be printed in the final document?"
  answers:
    - "Line 1"
    - "Line 2"
    - "Line 3"
    - "Line 4"
  correct: "Line 4"
  day: 4

- question: "What’s the primary purpose of putting tags on tasks?"
  answers:
    - "Adding metadata identifying what that task does"
    - "Allows selection of what tasks do and do not run"
    - "Gives the task a name to differentiate between other tasks"
  correct: "Allows selection of what tasks do and do not run"
  day: 4

- question: "When does a handler task run?"
  answers:
    - "Every time the 'tasks' section finishes."
    - "Only when notified by a task."
    - "Only when notified by a task AND that task created a change/turned yellow."
    - "Before the 'tasks' section begins."
  correct: "Only when notified by a task."
  day: 4

- question: "When you’re looking to download a new “toolkit” full of additional modules, you will likely download a _____:"
  answers:
    - "Role"
    - "Collection"
    - "Ansible Galaxy"
  correct: "Collection"
  day: 4

- question: "One of the most secure methods of entering something sensitive like a password that we've learned SO FAR would be:"
  answers:
    - "using vars_prompt"
    - "putting the password in the inventory file, unencrypted"
    - "putting the password in the playbook vars, unencrypted"
  correct: "using vars_prompt"
  day: 4

- question: "The Ansible controller that runs against a Dell EMC PowerEdge server would need the OMSDK installed via pip and the 'dellemc.openmanage' collection installed. What would the hosts/connection be in that playbook?"
  answers:
    - "dellemc, http"
    - "localhost, local"
    - "openmanage, ssh"
    - "dellemc, network_cli"
  correct: "dellemc, network_cli"
  day: 5

- question: "Why must we use a network_cli connection when using Ansible to configure most network devices?"
  answers:
    - "network devices can't receive SSH commands"
    - "expect scripting is inefficient, so we don't use it"
    - "network devices' OS doesn't permit Python to be installed"
    - "because everything has to be SO DARN DIFFICULT these days"
  correct: "network devices' OS doesn't permit Python to be installed"
  day: 5

- question: "What is a ROLE in Ansible?"
  answers:
    - "A highly organized playbook that can be imported into other playbooks."
    - "A group of modules grouped together in a single collection for easy download/installation."
    - "The plugin that allows for the Ansible Controller to talk to all kinds of hosts (Linux, network devices, cloud, etc.)"
  correct: "A highly organized playbook that can be imported into other playbooks."
  day: 5

- question: "What is ansible-vault?"
  answers:
    - "An encryption tool for files or strings that teams use for their playbooks."
    - "A storage tool that makes playbooks reusable by teams"
    - "A security tool that hides files so they are only detectable by the playbook."
  correct: "An encryption tool for files or strings that teams use for their playbooks."
  day: 5
